Guide to the Herbert Tuttle papers, 1880-1896.
Tuttle, Herbert papers, 1880-1896.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Herbert Tuttle papers, 1880-1896.
14-17-163
Herbert Tuttle, 1846-1894.
.9 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, lectures notes, course grade books, scrapbooks, obituaries, letters of condolence, personal account books, and correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Manuscripts, lectures notes, course grade books; scrapbooks containing reviews of his published works, obituaries, letters of condolence; personal account books, and correspondence.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Herbert Tuttle was Professor of Modern European History at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Manuscripts, lectures notes, course grade books; scrapbooks containing reviews of his published works, obituaries, letters of condolence; personal account books, and correspondence.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Tuttle, Herbert, 1846-1894.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. Dept. of History.
Subjects:
History--Study and teaching.; Professors.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Manuscript of a "History of Institutions" by Herbert Tuttle (Box 1-2)
- Title and synopsis of lectures in Modern History (Box 1-2)
- Prof. Tuttle's obituary notices and reviews of the fourth vol. of Prussian History (posthumous) (Box 1-2)
- Manuscript of Frederick the Great's campaign of 1758 by Tuttle (Box 1-2)
- Manuscript lectures on International Law by Tuttle (Box 1-2)
- Reviews of Tuttle's first three volumes of the "History of Prussia" (Box 1-2)
- One pamphlet containing printed letters relating to the contributions of Tuttle, written to Mrs. Tuttle after her husband's death [Mary McArthur?] (Box 1-2)
- Album of letters to Mrs. Tuttle on the death of her husband (Box 1-2)
- Letters of Horace Scudder and others concerning the fourth volume of "The History of Prussia," etc. (Box 1-2)
- Manuscript lectures (Box 1-2)
- Grade book, History of Institutions, 1890-1891 (Box 1-2)
- 2 account books (Box 1-2)
- 2 books of clippings (articles written by Tuttle?), 1880- (Box 1-2)
- Correspondence from A.D. White
  - Sept. 1, 1894 (Box 1-2)
  - Nov. 20, 1895 (Box 1-2)
- Correspondence from Herbert Baxter Adams to Mrs. Tuttle
  - July 27, 1894 (Box 1-2)
  - Aug. 15, 1894 (Box 1-2)
  - Sept. 14, 1894 (Box 1-2)
  - Oct. 6, 1894 (Box 1-2)
  - Oct. 27, 1894 (Box 1-2)
  - Nov. 12, 1894 (Box 1-2)
  - Dec. 8, 1894 (Box 1-2)
  - June 11, 1895 (Box 1-2)
  - Oct. 25, 1895 (Box 1-2)
  - Nov. 25, 1895 (Box 1-2)
  - Dec. 2, 1895 (Box 1-2)
  - Dec. 7, 1895 (Box 1-2)
  - Dec. 26, 1895 (Box 1-2)
  - Dec. 30, 1895 (Box 1-2)
  - Jan. 23, 1896 (Box 1-2)
  - Jan. 27, 1896 (Box 1-2)
  - Feb. 11, 1896 (Box 1-2)
  - Mar. 3, 1896 (Box 1-2)
- Postcard from John Morley, editor of Fortnightly Review, England, Feb. 4, 1877 (earliest ms. in collection) (Box 1-2)